# Dave Birch

Problem Solver, Front End Developer, Builder.

1309 Nightingale Drive Cedar Park, TX 78613 **T** 979.324.7346 **E** me@davebir.ch http://davebir.ch





#### Work Samples:

http://snoball.com http://blinksend.com

## **Synopsis**

Developing and implementing cohesive user experiences for web and mobile platforms.

Designing, developing and implementing effective brands – specializing in utilizing rich media to distribute messages

Team-player, life-long learner, dreamer. Driven to help build the best brands and the best companies.

### Skills

 Languages:
 Javascript: 8 years
 ActionScript 3 years

Python 2 years CSS/CSS3 8 years

HTML/HTML5 8 years

Technologies &JQueryDjangoSeleniumFrameworks:LESSTwitter BootstrapNoseTests

Tornado Adobe Creative Suite GIT

## **Experience**

### UX Developer/Creative Director & Co-Founder, Snoball Inc. Austin, TX. 2011 - Present

Responsible for branding, promotion and front end development of Snoball.com, while managing a small creative team for various projects. Tasks include converting legacy site design to a responsive, adaptive design. Developed front end interfaces utilizing JSON APIs for various user groups and client-specific Web, mobile, and site-specific apps (including Facebook and Foursquare apps).

## UX Developer/Creative Director & Co-Founder, Collective Labs. College Station, TX. 2011 - Present

Responsible for branding, promotion and front end development of Collective Labs and its two flagship products, BlinkSend and Snoball. Tasks include creation of motion graphics and videos, front-end design and interface development, assisting in implementation of usability enhancements to all sites and projects.

### UX Developer/Creative Director, Phodder LLC. College Station, TX. 2008 - 2010

As part of a web and mobile application consulting team, worked daily with clients managing projects, expectations and ensuring quality work, as well as managing a number of off-site contractors. Routinely created media for the IOS platform. Responsibilities included advising on and assisting in the development of effective brands and user interfaces.



Problem Solver, Front End Developer, Builder.

### Graphics Specialist, Texas A&M. VPAPIT Marketing. College Station, TX. 2004 - 2009

Developed and assisted in implementation of website front ends; assisting in several aspects of development starting with interface designs and frameworks, migrating to Photoshop mock-ups and developing into fully functional sites. Researched and implemented various mobile-friendly software solutions, utilizing modern Javascript and jQuery libraries.

Developed Flash applications including TAMULink interactive map, multi-video players and closed-caption video players. Developed several websites designs: it.tamu.edu, cis.tamu.edu, vpapit.tamu.edu, tamulink.tamu.edu, codemaroon.tamu.edu, cas.tamu.edu, security.tamu.edu

Developed print and multimedia pieces for several campaigns including Security Awareness Month '07 (Winner: IABC Silver Quill, Brazos Bravo, SIGUCCS) and Howdy promotional material (Winner: Brazos Brazo, SIGUCCS). Provided creative guidance and direction for the design of annual reports.

Produced marketing collateral, business identity, logos, trade booth displays, signage, web-site interface design and multimedia CD ROMS for the various groups and departments. Developed marketing and brand identities for Computer Information Services, Educational Broadcast Services, University Telecommunications, and Associate Provost for Information Technology and Council of Senior Business Administrators at Texas A&M University.

### **Education**

Azusa Pacific University, Azusa CA — 2001 BA Communication & Media Studies

### Referrals

Available Upon Request